Preliminary Guide to the Theodor Reik Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Theodor Reik papers
1947-1948
MS 1226
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
Principally the typescript draft for Theodor Reik's book, Listening with the Third Ear (1947). Also included are two chapters in manuscript form. In addition there is a letter to his publisher, John Farrar, with a copy of an article "The original 'Sleeping Beauty' discovered," which appears to be a literary hoax.
Reik, Theodor, 1888-1969
Biographical / Historical
Theodor Reik: associate of Sigmund Freud, University of Vienna, 1910-1938; lecturer in Vienna, Berlin, The Hague, New York, 1912-1944; director, Society for Psychoanalytic Psychology, N.Y., 1941-1970; professor of psychology, Adelphi University; author of many books.
Scope and Contents
Principally the typescript draft for Theodor Reik's book, Listening with the Third Ear (1947). Also included are two chapters in manuscript form. In addition there is a letter to his publisher, John Farrar, with a copy of an article "The original 'Sleeping Beauty' discovered," which appears to be a literary hoax.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Psychoanalysis; Authors; Psychologists; Reik, Theodor, 1888-1969
- Inventory
  - "The Original of the 'Sleeping Beauty' Discovered," 12:5 [ALS to John Farrar and printed copies], 1948 September (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Listening with the Third Ear [TMS]
    - Introduction, p. i-ix, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 1-8, p. 1-113a, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 9-16, p. 113b-224, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 17-22, p. 225-317, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 23-27, p. 318-393, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 28-31, p. 394-464, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chapters 32-35, p. 465-535, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chapters 36-44, p. 536-638, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Leave-Taking," p. 639-640a, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Listening with the Third Ear [AMS]
    - Chapter 6, Twenty-One Years After [chapter 5 in the typed manuscript. Titled: Twenty Years Later], [1947] (Box 2)
    - Chapter 3, How Freud Discovered Psychoanalysis [chapter 2 in the typed manuscript], [1947] (Box 2)